(コテツ)よっしゃ 任務終わり！
All right, our shift's over.
Time to close the gate.
(イズモ)閉門 閉門っと…。
この時間からの外出届は
出ていなかったはずだが…。
We didn't get any advance notices
about departures at this hour…
おい 閉門時間だぞ。
Hey, we're closing the gate!
待て…。
Wait!
Jiraiya Ninja Scrolls:
The Tale of Naruto the Hero-
Leaving the Village
(カカシ)サスケ。
Where are you going
at this hour?
(カカシ)こんな夜に
こんなことしてまで→
And why would you need
to resort to all this?
いったい
どこへ行こうっていうのかな？
(サスケ)アンタには感謝している。
I'm grateful to you…
だが まだ足りないんだ。
but this isn't enough.
I'm not satisfied with the lackluster level
that I'm at right now.
こんな生ぬるいところでは
それは得られない。
うん？
I'm going to get power…
俺は 力を手に入れる。
at the side of that
other Sannin.
もうひとりの三忍のもとで。
まさか お前…。
Don't tell me you're—?!
Damn it!
しまった！
もう遅い。
It's too late.
Sasuke!
サスケ…。
(綱手)うちはの幻術は きつい。
しばらくは動けんぞ。
The Uchiha's genjutsu
is powerful.
You won't be able to do
anything for a while.
Are you all right, Kakashi?
(ミナト)大丈夫かい？ カカシ。
Yes, never mind me. Sasuke's…
ええ それより サスケが…。
(ヒルゼン)先ほど
イズモとコテツから聞いた。
I heard earlier from
Izumo and Kotetsu.
Where is Sasuke heading
お前まで倒し サスケはいったい
どこへ向かったのじゃ？
that he'd resort to
hurting you as well?
おそらく 大蛇丸のところへ。
Most likely, to Orochimaru.
力を得るために。
To gain more power.
なんてことだ…。
What?
Orochimaru…?
大蛇丸…。
バカなことを。 そろそろ大蛇丸は→
That's so foolish!
Orochimaru will soon be looking
for his next vessel.
次なる器を欲する時期にきている。
自来也がそう言っていた。
サスケの身が危ない！
That's what Jiraiya said.
Sasuke is in danger!
《サクラ : そんな…》
No way!
We can't let Sasuke make contact
with Orochimaru.
サスケ君を大蛇丸に会わせてはダメだ。
それと 彼が里抜けしたことが
里内に広がるのは避けたい。
And…
I want to prevent any rumors
that he left the village from spreading.
至急 外出禁止令を
出そうと思います。
I'm going to issue
an urgent lockdown order.
うむ それがよかろう。
That's a good idea.
うちは一族の立場が これ以上
悪くならないためにも→
In order to prevent Uchiha's position
from worsening,
we must handle this internally
内々に そして速やかに
サスケ君を連れ戻さなければ。
and bring Sasuke back
quickly and smoothly.
NINJA ACADEMY
(ナルト)ハァ ハァ…。
いったい何だよ。
What's going on?
We're on lockdown,
but you called us to assemble…
外出禁止令が出てるのに
みんな集まれって。
I'll explain once everyone is here.
(シカマル)話は 全員 揃ってからだ。
Heh! What's with the attitude?
ヘッ！ なに
もったいぶってんだってばよ。
ん？ そういや
なんで教室に集合なんだ？
Oh, by the way, why are we meeting
in the classroom?
あ… ああ 他に思いつかなくてな。
U-Uh, I couldn't think
of anywhere else.
HOKAGE
へぇ～。
机とかイスって
こんなに小さかったっけ？
Were the desks and chairs
always this small?
No, we just got bigger.
(ヒナタ)ううん。
私たちが大きくなったの。
フッ そうだよな。
Guess you're right.
Sakura's eyes are
popping out of her head…
《サクラちゃん 目が イッちまってる。
What's so great about
that guy anyways?
こんなヤツのどこが
そんなにいいんだってばよ。
わからん》
I don't get it!
((テメエ ナルト！ サスケ君に
ガンたれてるんじゃないわよ！
Damn it, Naruto!
Don't glare at Sasuke!
どけ。
フン！
Move.
Just beat him up, Sasuke!
(いの)サスケ君 そんなヤツ
やっちゃいなよ！
そうよ そうよ！
That's right!
Huh? No way?!
Oops! Sorry!
(えっ!? ウソ！ あっ 悪ぃ！))
ん？
額当て…。
A headband…
A current Academy student wouldn't
have one of those yet.
(チョウジ)アカデミーの生徒は
まだ持てないよね。
(リー)すみません 遅くなりまして！
Sorry we're late!
(テンテン)もう！
アンタが逆立ちしながら来るから→
We're late because you insisted
on walking here on your hands.
遅れたんじゃない！
Are we the last ones?
(ネジ)俺たちが最後か？
Yeah, we're all here now.
ああ これで全員だ。
All here?
全員って サスケの野郎は？
What about that damn Sasuke?
そのサスケのことで面倒くせぇことが
起こっちまってな。
It's because of Sasuke that things
have become a bit of a drag.
なぁ サクラ。
(サクラ)う… うん。
Right, Sakura?
Uh…yeah!
私 病室の前でカカシ先生や
火影様の話を聞いちゃって…。
I was outside of
Lady Tsunade's office and
overheard Kakashi Sensei
and Lord Hokage talking…
Sasuke…left the village.
サスケが 里抜けしたらしい。
W-What?!
な… 何だって!?
(いの)サスケ君が!?
Sasuke did what?!
ど… どうして？
W-Why?
大蛇丸のもとに向かったそうだ。
He went to find Orochimaru.
よくわかんねえが 力を得るために
出ていっちまったらしい。
I don't know why, but he left
in order to get power.
Say… Isn't Orochimaru one
of the Legendary Sannin?!
(キバ)おい 大蛇丸って あの
伝説の三忍の１人じゃねえかよ。
Yeah… Furthermore, the rumor is
that he killed several villagers
(シノ)ああ しかも 里の人間を
何人も人体実験で殺し→
for his experiments and ran away
when he was discovered.
それがバレて 里を逃げ出した
という噂が。
そんなヤツのところへ…。
Why would he go to
someone like that?
今でさえ 危ない存在だってのに
どんな力をもらおうっていうのよ。
That man is still dangerous,
so what kind of power
is Sasuke seeking?
ナルト君…。
Naruto…
この額当て…。
This headband…
サスケのヤツ ここに来ていた。
Sasuke…was here.
木ノ葉の象徴である額当てを…。
The headband, which symbolizes
the Hidden Leaf…
しかも 俺たちの思い出の場所
アカデミーの教室に置いていった。
He left it here in
the Academy classroom,
which holds so many memories
for all of us.
つまり サスケは 俺たちを
木ノ葉を捨てたということか。
So in other words,
does it mean that Sasuke…
has abandoned us,
and the Hidden Leaf?
No way!
…んなわけねえよ！
Okay, so he's been a little irritable lately
and short with me,
確かに アイツは
ここんとこ ずっとイライラしてて→
俺に ガンたれてくるし
嫌なこと言うし→
and he said some sarcastic things
that made me mad…
俺だって ホント ムカついて
何なんだよって思って…。
だけどよ アイツは 木ノ葉の
俺たちの仲間だ！
But he's a Hidden Leaf…
he's our friend!
Naruto…
ナルト…。
大蛇丸は サスケ君の体を
器として乗っ取ろうとしてるの。
Orochimaru is going to
steal Sasuke's body
to use as his vessel…
サスケ君は そのことを知らない。
Sasuke doesn't know that.
サスケのヤツ… 何やってやがんだ。
What the hell is Sasuke doing?!
サスケを連れ戻すってばよ！
I'm gonna bring Sasuke back…
before he meets up with Orochimaru!
大蛇丸に会う前に 木ノ葉の里へ！
I'm bringing him back
to the village!
Hold on a minute.
まあ 待てよ
今 うちはの立場は→
We have to think of the position
the Uchiha are in too…
面倒くせぇことになってっからよ。
あまり 大事にはしたくねえ。
とはいえ ナルト１人だけに→
We can't make
a big deal out of this…
Still, we can't let Naruto go alone.
行かすわけには いかねえからな。
俺とナルトで行く。
So Naruto and I'll go.
ナルト！
Naruto!
I know, Sakura.
ああ わかってるってばよ
サクラちゃん。
I'll bring him back even if I have
to beat the hell outta him!
ぶん殴ってでも サスケのヤツを
連れて帰ってくるからよ。
(キバ)ヘヘッ 見ろよ。
ここが俺たちの秘密のトンネルだ。
See? This is our secret tunnel.
たまに赤丸と
月夜のピクニックと しゃれこんで→
Akamaru and I occasionally
go outside of the village
for fancy moonlight picnics.
里の外へ出かけるんだ。
(いの)何がピクニックよ。
ただの散歩じゃない。
Why are you calling it a picnic?
You just take him for walks!
そうよ いつか捕まるわよ！
Yeah! You're gonna get
caught one day!
そんなヘマするわけねえ。
I wouldn't mess up like that.
それに今は こいつのおかげで→
Besides, thanks to him,
we can go outside now,
向こう側 行けんだから
感謝してほしいな。
so you should be thankful.
シカマル そろそろ急がねえと。
ああ。
Shikamaru, we'd better hurry.
Yeah…
(サクラ)ナルト！
Naruto!
サクラちゃん！
Sakura?
ナルト お願い。
Naruto, please…
サスケ君を… サスケ君を
必ず連れ戻してきて！
Please bring Sasuke back,
no matter what!
大丈夫だって！
Don't worry!
サスケは ぜってぇ
俺が連れて帰る。
I'll bring Sasuke back.
約束するってばよ。
I promise you that!
頼んだぞ ナルト シカマル。
We're counting on you,
Naruto and Shikamaru.
ああ 任せろ！
Yeah, you bet!
《ナルト君… 気をつけて》
Naruto… Please be careful.
ん？
Sasuke boldly walked
out the front gate
サスケのヤツ 大門から
堂々と出ていくだけあって→
leaving clear tracks everywhere.
痕跡だらけだぜ。
おかげで追跡もしやすいがな。
That makes it easier to follow him.
《サスケ なんで…
なんでだってばよ》
Sasuke… Why?
Why did you—?
I'm…
《俺は…》
((フガク : はぁ～ やはり
イタチのときのようにはいかんか。
Why did I think you would
be like Itachi?
お前には
まだ早すぎたのかもしれんな。
Perhaps it's still too soon for you.
(イタチは同じ年頃には
完璧にできていたぞ))
Itachi was able to perfectly master it
when he was about your age.
《チクショウ！》
Damn it…
Chidori Stream!
((千鳥流し！
(ハァッ ハァッ ハァッ…))
《あの３年間を…》
Those three years…
((何だ この感じは…))
What is this feeling?
《あの３年間を
一瞬で終わらせてたまるか！》
I can't let those three years end
in a blink of an eye!
((ダンゾウ : うずまきナルト…。
Naruto Uzumaki…
He's gained a lot of strength
in three years.
(この３年で ずいぶん
力をつけたようだ))
《あの落ちこぼれが…。
That loser!
どんなことをしてでも
力を手に入れてやる！》
I'm going to obtain power,
no matter what it takes…
ミナト！
クシナ…。
Minato!
Kushina!
(クシナ)ねぇ 聞いてよ。
外出禁止令が出てるのに→
Listen to this…
Despite the lockdown order,
ナルトったら
いつの間にか家出ちゃって→
Naruto's snuck out and
gone off somewhere
まだ帰ってないのよ。
and hasn't come back.
Well uh… You're not supposed
to leave the house either.
いや キミも出てきちゃ
いけないんだけど…。
It's not only Naruto, ya know.
ナルトだけじゃないってばね。
Shikamaru's missing too.
シカマル君もいないらしくて。
え？
What?
サクラちゃんや いのちゃんは
家にいたんだけど→
Sakura and Ino were at home,
but something didn't seem right.
様子がおかしかったってばね。
何か隠してるような…。
It's like they were hiding something.
Hiding?
隠している？
うん。
Yeah.
例えば ナルトが不良になってて→
Like what if they saw examples of
Naruto becoming a delinquent,
夜な夜な いけない遊びに
出歩いてるのを→
like him going out every night,
doing something dangerous…?
And because Sakura and Ino
are just too nice,
サクラちゃんも いのちゃんも
優しいから→
私たちに心配をかけまいと…。
they didn't tell us because
they don't want us to worry…
って 聞いてるの？ ミナト！
あ あぁ…。
Are you even listening, Minato?!
Oh, yes.
ナルトなら大丈夫だよ。
Don't worry about Naruto.
I think he's probably out
doing some training.
おおかた どこかで修業でも
してるんだと思うよ。
This way!
こっちだ！
おう！
Right!
If Sasuke of the Uchiha Clan
leaves the village,
((うちはのサスケが里を出れば→
there will be a few who
will not stand idly by…
黙っておられぬ者どもが
出てくるだろう。
三代目から 四代目へ継承された
腑抜けた体制の申し子たちがな。
Mainly the children reared
by this cowardly system
that has been passed on by
the Third Hokage through to the Fourth.
ヤツらにつけ 動けば追え。
Keep watch on them,
and if they make a move,
follow them.
大蛇丸への
進物を無事届けねばならない。
I want the gift to Orochimaru
to reach him safely.
邪魔なら 排除しろ。
どんな手段を使ってもいい。
If they interfere, get rid of them.
Use whatever means necessary.
あるいは 動くのは
腑抜けだけとはかぎらぬ。
It's possible those fools won't be
the only ones on the move.
Therefore, I have gathered you,
the best of the Foundation.
ゆえに 根の者きっての
お前たちを こうして集めた。
(存分に励めよ))
Do your best.
Not good!
やばい！
Damn it!
クソッ！ しまっ…。
No…!
What?!
なに？
ゲジマユ！
Bushy Brows?!
ネジ テンテン。
Neji! Tenten!
どうして ここへ？
What are you doing here?
２人が里を出てすぐ
追いかけていく影を見た。
We saw some shadowy figures
pursuing you
as soon as you left the village.
で 急遽 俺たちが
助っ人に来たというわけだ。
And we hurried over to
be your back up.
やっぱり 留守番してるよりも→
I must say, being of help
like this
is much more invigorating than
just staying in the village!
こうやって皆さんの
お役に立てるほうが燃えますね！
Don't get too enthusiastic!
あまり 張り切り過ぎないでよ。
Nothing good happens
when you get too excited!
アンタが張り切ると
ロクなことないんだから。
No, get as enthusiastic
as you want.
いや 張り切ってもらうぜ
助かった。
You're a big help!
来る!!
Incoming!
お前たちは…。
You guys are—!
Those masks… !
その仮面… 暗部か？
They're ANBU?
って もう父ちゃんに
バレちまったのか。
Don't tell me Dad already
found out?!
追ってきたのは
この４人だけだ。
Only the four here…
followed us.
And there are five of us.
This will be easy!
僕たちは ５人です。
なんてこと ありませんよ！
はっ！ てやっ！
Sorry, but…
悪いがよ 父ちゃんの言いつけでも
引き下がれねえんだってばよ。
We can't retreat even if
Dad tells us to!
You idiots!
バカ！ お前たち 暗部相手に
何 まともに突っ込んでんだよ。
You can't just get into
a fight with the ANBU!
大蛇丸と会う前に→
We definitely have
to bring Sasuke back
サスケを連れ戻さなきゃ
ならねえんだってばよ！
before he meets up
with Orochimaru, ya know!
So please!
だから… 邪魔しないでくれ！
Don't get in our way!
ハーッ!!
くっ…。
Get back, everyone!
みんな 下がれ！
They're not ordinary ANBU…
《コイツら ただの暗部じゃねえな》
ナルト 大丈夫か？
《本気で 殺しに来てやがる。
いくらなんでも
外出禁止令を破ったくらいで→
やりすぎだろう。
そのうえ 火影の息子 ナルトまで
殺しにかかるなんて→
ありえねえ！》
そうか コイツら
火影直属の暗部じゃねえ。
三代目 四代目火影の
穏健派と違い→
武闘派の主任が
束ねていたという組織。
(シカマル)
今は 解散しているはずだが…。
昔 聞いたことがある。
暗部の中に 別動部隊として
暗部養成部門が存在していたと。
たしか 根の者と言っていた。
根？
《コイツらが 根の者!?》
《クソッ このままじゃ
サスケに追いつけねえ！》
＜今 人気絶頂の三山ひろしさんと
山内惠介さんが→
はるな愛さん 水谷千重子さんと
ペアを組んで突撃取材＞